When we want to use a LoRaWAN end device,
we must first activate it.
But what does activation really mean ?
Actually, it's quite simple.
Activation means that the end device is ready to send or receive LoRaWAN packet.
For that, we saw that we need to network session key for authentication, the application session key
for encryption on the device adress for identification. And these 3 sessions information
has to be both on the device and the server.
The question is how do the end device and the server can get these keys?
That's where the activation mode comes because there are two possible methods.
One is called ABP for Activation By Personalization.
It's supposed to be the simplest method, but it has also a lot of disadvantages.
There's also a second method called OTAA for Over The Air Activation.
And in that case, the activation procedure is a little bit more complex, but there are many advantages.
In both cases, the purpose is exactly the same.
We want to have the same network session key, application session key and the same device address in the end
device and on the server.
Now one more thing before diving in the activation process.
When we register a device on the LoRaWAN server, this device
must be uniquely identified.
This identification number is called the devEUI.
This devEUI is not supposed to be used twice.
Even if the ABP activation doesn't use it, the networks never will ask for this devEUI for the registration
because it can be helpful to identify your device on your server. Like any other LoRaWAN information
you can generate it on the network server.
But often, the devEUI is written on the box because it's not a secret number.
So now we're ready to study these two activation methods and in the next video let's start with ABP.